CONRAD MILLER

804-310-3682 ConradMillerDev@gmail.com

Timezone: MST UTC-7:00

www.conradrmiller.com

SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks

Typescript, Javascript, React, Redux, Java, Springboot, Python, Styled Components, Loopback.io

Technologies

React Testing Library,
Cypress, Mocha, OpenShift,
Kubernetes, Git, Gitlab CI/CD,
Splunk, REST API, Kibana,
Linux, AWS, AWS
Cloudwatch, Fenergo,
Guidewire

Hobbies

Robotics, Raspberry Pi, 3d Printing, Arduino, CAD

PROFILE

I am a software engineer with 4+ years of experience developing React UIs and Java APIs along with testing and dev-ops processes to deliver code to production. I have a passion for developing a great user experience and the backend systems that support both the experience and the business. I love learning new technologies and creatively implementing them to solve problems. I have a background in financial services and retail management that gives me a unique perspective on creating user experiences that are engaging and effective, allow me to understand the needs of the business, and make me a powerful asset to any team I am a part of.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Silicon Valley Bank (SVB), Tempe, AZ — June 2022-Present

- The Portico project is a configuration driven sales experience that allows SVB to onboard clients globally and integrate them into SVB's systems. I developed the user interface, backend APIs, component libraries, related tests, and integrations for the Portico sales acquisition flow. I utilized and integrated with our SAAS platform (Fenergo) to confirm and validate configurations and business rules. My contributions along with my team allowed the project to meet it's go live date and begin customer facing service in October of 2022. (Typescript, React, Redux, Node.js, Loopback.io, GitLab, Gitlab CI/CD, Cypress, Openshift, AWS)
- I was responsible for testing all of my code contributions using both unit tests and cypress functional testing strategies. I contributed to a testing sprint that involved a multi team effort of end to end testing the entire application and all downstream systems. These efforts allowed the teams to effectively identify, track, and resolve any bugs before users were impacted.
- I documented my process to onboard to the project to facilitate the
 onboarding of 3rd party contractors and new hires. I reviewed, amended,
 and created training material and documentation that would allow new
 members of the team to ramp up more effectively and efficiently I
 interviewed, supported, and trained newly onboarded members of the
 team to help them become contributors as quickly as possible.

Software Engineer, USAA, Phoenix, AZ — 2018-June 2022

- I developed the UI for the new small business insurance product. The product was the first new product in 30+. The UI was architected to be dynamic based on configuration files allowing the product owner to make rapid changes based on sales data. (Javascript, React, Redux, Styled Components, Openshift, Gitlab CI/CD, Gitlab, Guidewire)
- I implemented the dev-ops system for the small business insurance project including; gitLab CI/CD pipelines, React Testing Library unit tests, Cypress functional and accessibility tests, production deployments to OpenShift, logging and dashboards in Splunk, and alerts in Slack. (GitLab CI/CD, RTL, Cypress, OpenShift)
- I developed a rest API for the schedule a call project. The application replaced a legacy project and involved legacy code documentation and changes as well as new code development. (Java, Springboot, REST API)
- I worked on the deployment and testing process for the new life insurance quoting experience. I researched taught the team the process for deploying to production on our new platform. I helped close code coverage testing gaps on the apis for the experience and clean the code for production. (Java, JBOSS, JUnit, Gitlab CI/CD)

Sr. Financial Advisor, USAA, Phoenix, AZ — 2014-2018 Stock Broker, Schwab, Phoenix, AZ — 2013-2014

EDUCATION

Western Governors University - IT Management - B.S. Business Administration - 2018